(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Welcome!2000
作詞：コゲどんぼ / 作曲：坂本裕介
Lyrics: Koge-Donbo / Composition: Yusuke Sakamoto
Welcome to Welcome to Welcome to my house
生まれたての 朝陽が ササン
The freshly born morning sun is shining brightly
水と森が 光って キラキラ
The water and forest are sparkling and glittering
今日もお掃除 ピカピカ
Cleaning today too, making it shiny
猫の手も借りたい くらいだにょ
I'm so busy I'd even take a cat's help, nya
つまらないこと 気にしないにょ
Don't worry about boring things, nya
ミスっちゃっても 転んじゃっても 前向きに ゴーゴー
Even if I make a mistake or fall down, go go positively
今日もあたしは おおいそがし
I'm very busy today too
疲れちゃっても 戦闘モードにょ
Even if I get tired, I'm in battle mode, nya
Welcome to Welcome to Welcome to my house
頑張るにょ ちょっとだけ どじなあたしでも
I'll do my best, even if I'm a bit of a klutz
Welcome to Welcome to Welcome to my house
今日も君が 来てくれるの
You're coming to see me again today
待ってるにょ
I'm waiting for you, nya
沈んでゆく 夕陽は ユラユラ
The setting sun is swaying
迷子の子猫は ふわふわ
The lost kitten is fluffy
今日も足元 フラフラ
Wobbly feet again today
お日様も ご苦労様だにょ
Good job to the sun too, nya
過ぎちゃったこと 振り返らないにょ
Don't look back at what's already passed, nya
失敗しちゃっても 恥ずかしくっても 後悔は ノノ
Even if I fail or feel embarrassed, no regrets, no-no
いつもあたしは おおいそがし
I'm always very busy
落ち込まないで 戦闘モードにょ
Don't get depressed, I'm in battle mode, nya
Welcome to Welcome to Welcome to my house
頑張るにょ ちょっとだけ どじなあたしでも
I'll do my best, even if I'm a bit of a klutz
Welcome to Welcome to Welcome to my house
今日も君が 来てくれるの
You're coming to see me again today
待ってるにょ
I'm waiting for you, nya
足音 パタパタ
Pitter-patter of footsteps
お掃除 ピカピカ
Cleaning, shiny
夕陽は ユラユラ
The setting sun is swaying
子猫は ふわふわ
The kitten is fluffy
つまらないこと 気にしないにょ
Don't worry about boring things, nya
ミスっちゃっても 転んじゃっても
Even if I make a mistake or fall down
過ぎちゃったこと 振り返らないにょ
Don't look back at what's already passed, nya
失敗しちゃっても 恥ずかしくっても
Even if I fail or feel embarrassed
落ち込まないで 戦闘モードにょ
Don't get depressed, I'm in battle mode, nya
Welcome to Welcome to Welcome to my house
頑張るにょ ちょっとだけ どじなあたしでも
I'll do my best, even if I'm a bit of a klutz
Welcome to Welcome to Welcome to my house
今日も君が 来てくれるの
You're coming to see me again today
待ってるにょ
I'm waiting for you, nya
Waiting for you!
にょ、にょ、にょ、待ってるにょ
Nyo, nyo, nyo, waiting for you!
待ってるにょ
Waiting for you!
はぁ…、はぁ…、はぁ…
*Heavy breathing*
ごめんね！
Sorry!
えー、皆さん…
Um, everyone...
初めましての方は、初めまして。
Nice to meet you if it's your first time.
私、ホロライブ3期生、不知火フレアと申します！
I am Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Generation!
Overseas brothers, hello!
My name is Flare Shiranui.
1曲目でこんなヘロヘロで大丈夫か？
Am I going to be okay being this exhausted after just one song?
今日はですね、私誕生日、生誕祭ライブにお集まりいただきまして、本当に、本当にありがとうございます！
Today is my birthday, and thank you all so much for gathering for this birthday celebration live!
なんか最初からね、待機所でも既にスーパーチャットとかたくさん投げていただいて、本当に、本当にありがとうございます。
From the start, you've been sending so many Super Chats in the waiting room, thank you all so very much.
今回ですね、たくさん、あの、楽曲とかを用意して、
I've prepared many songs this time,
みんなに楽しんでいただく準備はできておりますので、最後まで楽しんでいただけたら嬉しいです。
and am ready for everyone to enjoy them, so I hope you enjoy the show until the end.
で、ですね、こちら…ちょっとごめん、ちょっと疲れちゃった。
And also, this... sorry, I'm a bit tired.
えっと、こちらですね、見える、これ？
Um, this, can you see this?
こちらハッシュタグありますので、よかったらTwitterでいっぱいツイートしてくれたら嬉しいです！
We have a hashtag here, so I'd be happy if you could tweet about it a lot on Twitter!
目指せ、トレンド1位！
Let's aim for #1 trending!
私をトレンド1位に連れてって？
Won't you take me to the top of the trends?
たっちゃん？たっちゃんって誰よ。
Touch-san? Who is Touch-san?
あっ、なんか動画が届いてるらしいんだ。
Oh, it seems like a video has arrived.
サプライズ動画らしいんだけど、ちょっと見てみようか。
It seems to be a surprise video, let's take a look.
誰？
Who is it?
どなた？
Who could it be?
おめーかよ！
Oh, it's you!
お姉ちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Onee-chan, happy birthday!
ハニーストラップの周防パトラです！
I'm Suo Patra from HoneyStrap!
今日はね、フレアちゃんに誕生日プレゼントを持ってきました～！
Today, I brought a birthday present for Flare-chan!
まじか、イェーイ！
Really? Yay!
フレアちゃんに歌ってほしい曲があって、
There's a song I want Flare-chan to sing,
オケを作ったから、ぜひ歌ってほしいな～なんて思ってます！
so I made a backing track for it and would love for you to sing it!
すごい、動画編集凝ってるな。
Wow, the video editing is really elaborate.
みんな～、フレアちゃんの歌を聴け～！
Everyone, listen to Flare-chan's singing!
ではでは！
Well then!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ノエルちゃんと末長くお幸せにね！
I hope you and Noel-chan stay happy forever!
はい。
Right.
周防パトラでした～！バイバ～イ！
This was Suo Patra! Bye-bye!
あ、抱き枕、抱いて、抱いて…
Oh, and hug your body pillow...
うるせーな！
Shut up!
パトラありがとう！
Thank you, Patra!
っていうね、まあ前振りをいたところなんですけど、今回の楽曲に関しまして、
So that was a bit of a lead-in, but regarding the songs for this live,
パトラにね、いろいろスケジュールとか忙しい合間を縫ってもらって、
Patra took time out of her busy schedule,
「フレアちゃん誕生日だからね」って言って、楽曲を何曲か作ってくれたんですよ。
saying, "Since it's Flare-chan's birthday," and made several backing tracks for me.
なので、どれがパトラが作ったかとか、そういう話はまた後日お話しさせていただけたらなーって思うんですけど。
So, I'd like to talk more about which ones Patra made on another day.
ちょっと最後の抱き枕に関してはちょっと、いらねーな、うるせーな、って。
Though that last bit about the body pillow was unnecessary and annoying.
いつもありがとうね、パトラ。
Thanks as always, Patra.
そしてお誕生日プレゼントってことで、素敵な曲をいただきましたので、
And since I received such a wonderful song as a birthday present,
早速ですけどね、ちょっと1曲…これはパトラが制作してくれた曲なんで、ぜひぜひちょっと聴いていただきたいな、という。
I'd like to get right into it. This is a song Patra made, so I definitely want you to listen to it.
私がずっと、あの、歌いたいなーって思ってたんですけど、オケがなかったので、歌えなかった曲なので。
It's a song I've always wanted to sing, but couldn't because there was no backing track for it until now.
ちょっと早速、2曲目行きたいなと思います。
So without further ado, let's move on to the second song.
はい、では聴いてください。
All right, please listen.
「絶望と希望」
"Despair and Hope"
悲しみ痛みは always 誰にも言えなくてそっと
Sadness and pain are always kept hidden away quietly
電話の後に
After a phone call
こぼれ落ちてゆく words
Words that spill out
どうせ一人ぼっちなんてバカな泣き虫
Calling myself "alone anyway," what a foolish crybaby
人は心に
People keep in their hearts
逃げ道を作ってる
An escape route they've built
知らないうちに弱さ
Without realizing it, holding onto their weakness
握りしめて
tightly
…めるよ
…will find you.
人混みに埋め尽くされた街の上に
Above the city filled with crowds,
孤独な空がある いつもきっと
There is a lonely sky. Always, I'm sure,
大地を見ては私を探していた
I was looking for myself while watching the earth.
今日という波が砂浜に打ち寄せて
When the waves of today wash upon the shore,
しぶきを上げるとき この涙が
And the spray rises, these tears
海に落ちるよ 拾い集めた
Will fall into the sea. I've gathered
いつかの夢の破片
the fragments of some dream.
届いて My dream
Reach me, my dream.
強がるだけのEverydays
Every day of just acting tough,
大人になれないもどかしさが続いてく
The frustration of not being able to grow up continues.
長い夜はSlowly
On long nights, slowly,
誰かに慰めてもらっても なぜか虚しい
Even if someone comforts me, it feels empty.
部屋の隅には 懐かしいオルゴールの音
In the corner of the room, a nostalgic music box,
静かな歌が心締めつけてくるよ
A quiet song tightens my heart.
過去と今とが重なり駆け抜けていく
Past and present overlap and race through.
心の交差点 壊れそうなガラスの扉
The intersection of the heart, a fragile glass door,
今この手で開こう
I will open it now with these hands.
絶望と希望との間には何が立ち尽くしているの?
What is standing still between despair and hope?
目を閉じて思い浮かべる
I close my eyes and imagine
心の中 散らばる夢の破片
The fragments of dreams scattered in my heart.
あなたにもあるよ
You have them too.
世界中で一番 ちっぽけな生き物だもの
We are the smallest creatures in the world.
人は押し流されて生きていくよ
People live on while being swept away.
たったひとつの勇気があればよかった
If only I had just one bit of courage.
それだけでこんなに傷つくことを
Just with that, from being hurt so much,
逃げ出さないでこの道歩けたのに
I could have walked this road without running away.
これから巡っていく季節と無常な闇風の中で
In the seasons and the heartless dark wind to come,
誰かを愛し 誰かのために戦っていくんだね
You'll love someone and fight for someone.
きっと最後まで走り続ける強さはその答えなんだろう
Surely, the strength to keep running is the answer.
負けないように 忘れないように
So as not to lose, so as not to forget,
もう一度瞳を空を見上げるから
I will lift my eyes to the sky once more.
はい、お聴きいただきました曲は、川嶋あいさんの「絶望と希望」という曲でした。
Yes, that song was "Zetsubou to Kibou" by Ai Kawashima.
私の大好きなアーティストさんの曲なんですけど、
It's a song by an artist I really love...
前々からちょっと歌いたいなと思っていたので、本当に本当に歌えて嬉しい。ありがとうね。
...and I've wanted to sing it for a long time, so I'm really happy I could. Thank you.
ちょっとお水飲んでいいですか？
Can I take a sip of water?
あ、ありがとうございます。あ、運営さんがめちゃくちゃ親切。
Oh, thank you. Wow, the staff are being so kind.
あー、おいしい。お水がおいしい。
Ah, refreshing. The water tastes great.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
あ、そういえばね、ちょっとツッコミ忘れてたんですけど、ここにね、今までいなかった、あの、金のツバがいらっしゃるんですよ。
Oh, that's right, I forgot to mention, there's a Golden Tsuba here that wasn't here before.
でもね、ちょっと次の曲はですね、あの、今回最初で最後の、あの、ちょっと…
But, the next song... well, it's the first and last of its kind for this time...
コラボ曲というか、ちょっとゲスト一人呼んでるのですけど...
A collaboration song, or rather, I've invited a guest...
あの、ちょっと邪魔なので、ちょっとはけていただこうかと...
She's a bit in the way, so I thought I'd have her step aside for a moment...
はい、アルパカパトちゃん。
Yes, Alpaca Pato-chan.
ちょっとこいつ、ちょっと一旦はけてもらって。
Please have this one step aside for now.
で、ですね、
Now then,
皆さん、今ね、楽しんでいただけてると思いますけれども、
everyone, I'm sure you're enjoying yourselves right now, but...
地獄が始まります。
the hell is about to begin.
ちょっと今から地獄が始まりますよ。
The hell is starting from now.
何の曲ですか？ちょっと聞かせていただきたいと思いますけれど。
What song is it? I'd like to let you hear it, but...
はい、ではですね。
Alright then.
曲のタイトル言っちゃいたいと思います。
I'll announce the song title.
チューリングラブ。
Turing Love.
チューリングラブ
作詞・作曲：ナユタセイジ
Turing Love
Lyrics/Composition: Nayuta Seiji
あー恋の定義がわかんない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love
まず設定基準もわかんない
First, I don't know the setting criteria either
要は恋してるときが恋らしい
Basically, when you're in love, it's like love
客観 主観 エビデンスプリーズ
Objective, subjective, evidence please
愛は計算じゃ解けない？
Can't love be solved with calculations?
まず普通の計算も解けない
First, I can't even solve normal calculations
要はそんな状態が愛らしい
Basically, that state is lovely
I know, You know, もう回天の...
I know, You know, anymore, of the revolution...
実証においてQがあって Aを出して 解けるのに
In the demonstration, there's a Q, and you give an A, and it's solvable
勘違いして 間違えて 解のないこの気持ちはなんだろう
Mistaken, erroneous, what is this feeling with no answer?
検証、数、目りゃ、熱情、モーションは相対性にSay!
Verification, numbers, if you look, passion, motion to relativity, Say!
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love, even if we gaze at each other, an unsolvable mellow
ワンスター、ツー、ステップ、イマ ワンスター、ツー、ステップで明かそうか
One star, two, step, now, with one star, two, step, shall we reveal it?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン ハートで高鳴るアンサー
A question created with words, an answer throbbing in the heart
測って 不確定性 僕らのBPM
Measure the uncertainty, our BPM
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったって信じないけど
Turing Love, even if it dances in the air, I don't believe it
フォーリンラブ イマは A、B、C、ズラ ラブリソースだ
Fall in love, now, it's A, B, C, shifted, it's a love resource
何でか教えておいら
Tell me why, me
感想聞かせてゼッパ
Let me hear your thoughts, Zeppa
予測不可可能性 今触れてみる
Unpredictable possibility, I'll try touching it now
さあ、証明しよう
Come on, let's prove it
間違いのないように証明しよう
Let's prove it so there are no mistakes
この感情全部全部
All of these feelings, all of them
証明しよう 正解があるなら証明しよう
Let's prove it, if there's a correct answer, let's prove it
シンプルなQ.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい
I want to prove it today
目に見えない無理なんだよ
It's an invisible impossibility
A.S.A.P.導き出したい
I want to derive it ASAP
たどり着きたい最適解へ
I want to reach the optimal solution
何度も空回ったって ぶつかっちゃったって
No matter how many times I've gone in circles or bumped into things
不可思議なこのアノマリーを解き明かす仮定、必要条件です
to unravel this mysterious anomaly, it's a hypothesis, a necessary condition
3次元カッコ立体における2点 A、B間の距離を求めよ
In 3D, that is, a solid, find the distance between two points, A and B
素敵な感じだと思っていたのに
I thought it was a wonderful feeling, but...
公式も見当たらないし
And I can't even find a formula
先行資料にも載っていないから君と生み出してみたいじゃん
Since it's not in previous literature either, I want to create it with you
3次元カッコ世界におけるこの気持ちの求め方
In 3D, that is, the world, the way to find this feeling
マルだって バツだって 不安だって 行こうよ
Even if it's a circle, an X, or anxiety, let's go
近くなって 遠くなって 揺れるこの気持ちの針も
Getting closer, getting further, even the needle of these swaying feelings
条件付きステップ エモーションは相対性にSay!
Conditional, step, emotion to relativity, Say!
チューリングラブ 騒ぎ出した胸の痛くなるほど
Turing Love, as much as my chest starts to ache
証明は 今も角度増しているようだ
The proof seems to be gaining more angles even now
曖昧も除外して 最大の仮説
Exclude ambiguity as well, the greatest hypothesis
今、二人なら実証できそう
Now, the two of us seem able to demonstrate it
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love, even if we gaze at each other, an unsolvable mellow
ワンスター、ツー、ステップ、イマ ワンスター、ツー、ステップで明かそうか
One star, two, step, now, with one star, two, step, shall we reveal it?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン ハートで高鳴るアンサー
A question created with words, an answer throbbing in the heart
測って 不確定性 僕らのBPM
Measure the uncertainty, our BPM
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったってその因果も
Turing Love, even if it dances in the air, that causality too
フォーリンラブ イマは X、Y、Z、ズラ ラブリソースだ
Fall in love, now, it's X, Y, Z, shifted, it's a love resource
確かめさせてピタゴラス
Let me confirm, Pythagoras
確かにさせて今
Let it be certain now
予測不可可能性 今触れてみる
Unpredictable possibility, I'll try touching it now
さあ、証明しよう
Come on, let's prove it
間違いのないように証明しよう
Let's prove it so there are no mistakes
この感情全部全部
All of these feelings, all of them
証明しよう 正解があるなら証明しよう
Let's prove it, if there's a correct answer, let's prove it
時速を越えて証明しよう
Let's prove it beyond speed
間違いのないように証明しよう
Let's prove it so there are no mistakes
この感情全部全部
All of these feelings, all of them
証明しよう 正解があるなら証明しよう
Let's prove it, if there's a correct answer, let's prove it
シンプルなQ.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
はあ...
Hah...
低いね！
It's low!
でも出ないだろ？
But you can't hit it, right?
そう、あの、フレアのところは高いから。
Right. Um, Flare's part is high.
男女、男女です。
It's male and female, male and female.
あ、ということで高くも低くもね、少々、歌えないから。
Oh, so both high and low, well, I can't quite sing it.
ノエルの限界がきた。
Noel's reached her limit.
ちょっと飲み物飲んでもいい？
Can I drink some water?
あ、飲む飲む？
Oh, drink?
いっぱい飲んでください。
Please drink a lot.
はあ...
Hah...
さっきフレアが歌ってるとき、団長、いっぱい飲んだから。
While Flare was singing earlier, Captain, I drank a lot.
大丈夫。
It's okay.
というわけでですね、
And so,
今回あの、やっぱりね、ノエルちゃんをちょっとゲストにお呼びしたいなと思って、
I really wanted to invite Noel-chan
as a guest for this event,
え、誰が地獄やねんな。
Hey, who are you calling "hell"?
確かに地獄だったけども...（笑）
It certainly was hell, though... (laughs)
みんなのコメント見てみようよ。
Let's take a look at the comments.
え、すごいパチパチって書いてある！
Oh, look at all the clapping!
ありがとう！拍手拍手！てぇてぇも見たよ！
Thank you! Claps! I see "teetee" comments too!
ありがとうございます。ふふ、頑張りました。
Thank you very much. Hehe, we did our best.
しかしどこまでが本当なんだろう、このコメント。
I wonder how many of these comments are real.
え、なになに、なんでよ、本物でしょよ！
Eh, what? Why would you say that? They're real!
でもね、ノエルちゃんと一緒にずっと歌いたかったんだけど、
But you know, I've always wanted to sing
with Noel-chan...
ノエルちゃんが...私がね、ノエルちゃんが歌いやすい曲と...
Noel-chan... I tried to find a song
that would be easy for her to sing...
おめえの話に入んだよ！（笑）
Get in on the conversation! (laughs)
主人公はね、フレアだから、団長ちょっとガヤに...（笑）
Flare is the star, so the Captain
will just provide backup... (laughs)
ノエルちゃんと一緒に歌いたい曲がちょっと二曲ぐらいあったんだけど、
There were about two songs
I wanted to sing with her,
どっちがいい？って聞いたら、ノエルちゃん何故かこっちを選んだんだよね。
and when I asked which was better,
she chose this one for some reason.
いや、だってさ、てぇてぇじゃん、てぇてぇじゃん、
Well, because it's so precious, right? Precious!
てぇてぇからさ、歌いたいじゃん、歌えなくてもね！
It's so precious that I wanted to sing it,
even if I couldn't do it well!
いや、でもね、その気持ちが私はすごい嬉しかった。
But you know, that sentiment made me really happy.
頑張った、頑張った、頑張った！これめっちゃね、伝わった、頑張った感は出たでしょ。
We tried hard! That effort definitely came through,
don't you think?
頑張った！しゅっしゅっしゅ。
We did our best! Swish, swish, swish.
動きだけでもぴょんぴょんと。
We were hopping around with just our movements.
でもやっぱ歌いながらさ、ちょっとムズい！ってなったけど、
But while singing, it was like, "This is hard!"
唐突にさ、ノエルちゃんにも唐突にお願いしたからさ、
I asked Noel-chan quite suddenly too,
突貫工事だった、ごめんね、と思って。
so it was a rush job. I felt bad about that.
速いところやっぱ噛んじゃった。
I definitely tripped over the fast parts.
いやー、ムリだー！でも、練習の時の方がいけたじゃん！
It's impossible! But we did better in practice!
最初の方の中ではいけたやん！って思ったの。
I thought we did okay in the beginning!
頑張って練習しました。
I practiced really hard.
二回目のやつがちょっとカクカクってなっちゃって、
The second one got a bit jerky,
本当にお邪魔してます、ありがとうございます。
so I'm really sorry for intruding. Thank you.
ううん、ノエルちゃん、ありがとうね、来てくれて。
No, Noel-chan, thank you so much for coming.
でですね、今回このNSSSの衣装っていうのが、滅多にないと思うので、
And so, since we rarely get to wear
these NSSS outfits together,
今日はノエフレで写真撮影会をちょっぴりだけ時間取らせてもらおうかなって思って。
I thought we'd take a little time
for a Noe-Fure photo shoot today.
私の思い出作りに付き合って！
Join me in making some memories!
いっぱい撮って、ハッシュタグで思い出をいっぱいツイートしてくれたら嬉しい！
Take lots of photos and tweet them
with the hashtag. That would make me happy!
レッツ！どうする？
Let's go! What should we do?
あのさ、さっきのリハーサルでさ、やってたやつやろうよ。
Hey, let's do that thing we did
in the rehearsal earlier.
みんなオルタナティブ好きというかなんか、
Everyone likes that "Alternative" vibe...
クールな私とノエフレちょっと見てて。
Take a look at the cool version of us.
ちょっとかっこよく、かっこよく写して。
Make us look cool, capture it coolly.
かっこいいじゃん！やっぱ背中合わせって神なんだよね。
We look cool! Back-to-back is just divine.
こうやって手を差し伸べる感じ。
Like this, reaching out our hands.
ちょっとプルプルしてきた。さっきの疲れが。
I'm starting to shake. From exhaustion earlier.
どう？ノエルちゃんもうちょっと反って。あ、いい！もうちょっと反って。
How's this? Noel-chan, lean back more. Ah, good!
A bit more.
撮れた撮れた！かっこよく撮れた？
Got it! Did it look cool?
あとさ、もう一個あったじゃん。もう一個やってもらおうよ。
There was one more, right? Let's do another one.
そう、これね、やっぱライブをしてる...うーん！
Right, this one. Since we're doing a live... Hngh!
待って、ノエルちゃん体硬い！
Wait, Noel-chan, your body is so stiff!
来てる来てる？どう、これできてる？みんなできてる？
Is it working? How is it? Are we doing it?
Everyone, are we?
足はダメ！ちょっとアップして、引っ込むな、引っ込むな！やめろやめろ！
Not the legs! Zoom in... don't pull back!
Stop, stop it!
愛がちょっと、裏返しの。ドスダイアーの中の闇みたいな。
The love is a bit... inside out. Like the
darkness within.
ちょっと見ちゃいけないものが...下の部分は見せちゃいけない部分だったね。
There's something we shouldn't see...
The lower half was off-limits.
これなんか、みんなにもコメントとか、せっかくだからどんなポーズがいいか聞きましょう。
Let's ask everyone in the comments
what kind of poses they want to see.
今草しか生えてないよ。草。草。草。
Only "grass" (lol) is growing now. Lol. Lol. Lol.
芝刈り機やって、芝刈り機。
Do the lawnmower, the lawnmower.
芝刈り機！ドゥルドゥルドゥル...わぁ！
Lawnmower! Vroom vroom vroom... waah!
なんでちょっと芸人になっちまうんだ。
Why are we turning into comedians?
ハイタッチ、ハイタッチ。でもちょっとカウンターバグがあるかも。
High touch, high touch. But there might be
a counter bug.
エイ！エイ！エイ！頑張って！見えざる壁が...
Ei! Ei! Ei! Do your best! An invisible wall...
でもね、付いてますから。気持ちは付いてるから。
But we're connected. Our hearts are connected.
あとは？おお、あ、タイタニック！タイタニック！
What else? Oh, Titanic! Titanic!
ルルルル...あ、私身長一緒なんでちょっと...
Lululu... Ah, our heights are the same,
so it's a bit...
見えなくなっちゃった。それこそコスプレイヤーのあれよ。
I've disappeared. That's a total cosplayer move.
どう？タイタニック！沈没しちゃう。運営さんが頑張った。
How's that? Titanic! We're sinking. The staff worked hard.
あ、ノエルちゃん逆やって、逆！やるやるやる！
Ah, Noel-chan, swap positions! Let's do it!
ちょっと足、これ...足が！プルプル...
The legs... my legs! They're shaking...
あとは？電車ごっこやる？私先頭！
What else? Should we play train? I'll be the lead!
見てて、プップー！プップー！
Watch this! Choo choo! Choo choo!
目的地どこだこれ？
Where is this train even heading?
何がいいの？でもさ、団長昨日ほら、お風呂でさ、ドライブ...
What's good? But Captain, yesterday in the bath,
remember the "drive"...
練習してたじゃん。団長もさ、ほら...
We were practicing. I also, you know...
あの結構ね、あの某ゲームで...
In that certain game...
運転上手いって言われてるから助手席乗ってよ。
I'm told I'm a good driver, so get in the passenger seat.
はい、助手席。
Here, passenger seat.
行くぞ！
Let's go!
なんで！もう乗ってよ。
Why! Just get in already.
それ何してるときのやつ？
What are you doing there?
え、今アクセル全開。
Um, full throttle right now.
びゅーんって。
Vroom!
これ運転してる姿だそうですね。
So this is her driving pose.
お分かりいただけたでしょうか。
Did you all get that?
楽しいですね。
This is fun.
いや一緒にドライブしようね、今度は。
No, let's go for a drive together next time.
私が運転しようか。
How about I drive?
あ、じゃあ団長助手席。
Oh, then I'll be in the passenger seat.
何人引くでしょうか。
I wonder how many people I'll run over.
やだ、怖い。
No, scary!
誕生日に何言ってんだよ。
What am I saying on my birthday?
平和に行きたいな。
I want to live in peace.
平和にね。
In peace.
あと何かある？
Anything else?
あ、さ、観客席...みんなとさ、撮りたくない？写真。
Oh, look, the audience... don't you want to take a photo with everyone?
あ、撮りたい、撮りたい、撮りたい。
Ah, I want to, I want to, I want to.
みんなー！
Everyone!
エルフレのみんなとか。
With all the Elfriends.
いや、ゲストだからね、団長は。そうそう。
Well, I'm a guest, after all. Right.
みんなー！
Everyone!
イェーイ！手繋ぎたい。
Yay! I want to hold hands.
手繋ぐ？
Hold hands?
手繋ぎたい。
I want to hold hands.
みんなー！アリーナ！
Everyone! Arena!
2階席！
Second floor seats!
来てくれてありがとうね。
Thank you for coming.
写真撮影、ピースピース。
Photo time, peace peace.
私たちセンスなさすぎてさ、リハーサルの時にさ...
We have so little sense, during rehearsal...
どんなポーズとる？って言ってさ。
We were like, "What pose should we do?"
ずっとカメラに向かってダブルピースするしか。
All we could do was double peace at the camera.
ちょっとカメラさんアップにして。
Camera-san, zoom in a bit.
こう！
Like this!
イェーイ！
Yay!
やめなさい。
Stop it.
ね、それやめな...
Hey, stop that...
ちょっと痛い人みたいになっちゃったじゃん。
I look like a painful person now.
一瞬バック映すのやめて。
Stop showing the back for a second.
ねー、したって。ピース。
Come on, do it. Peace.
でもチューリングラブ。
But Chu-ring Love.
ちゅ。
Chu.
でもこれね、私たちさ、あの裏で練習してたじゃん。
But you know, we were practicing this backstage.
そしたらさ、颯爽と現れたさ、スタッフさんの方が上手かった。
Then a staff member appeared out of nowhere and was better at it.
こうですよ、みたいな言うこともなく、目の前でね。
Without saying "like this," right in front of us...
リズムに合わせてなんか書いてきながら。
Drawing while matching the rhythm.
チュ・チュ・チュ・チュ・チュ...
Chu, chu, chu, chu, chu...
面目ないんだけど。
It's embarrassing.
出る、焦る。
We're coming out, getting flustered.
負けてらんねえ、ってちょっとギリギリまで練習してた。
We were like "we can't lose," and practiced until the last second.
イェーイ！
Yay!
あれしたい。
I want to do that.
何？
What?
何これ？
What's this?
お米？
Rice?
違う！
No!
団長、ちょっと待って。はい。
Dancho, wait a sec. Okay.
これ多分映る？これ。
Is this probably being shown?
なんでさ、大きいハートじゃなくて小さいの選ぶの？
Why did you choose a small heart instead of a big one?
あ、こうか、こうして...
Oh, like this, like this...
団長が上か。
I'm on top?
髪の毛が。
My hair.
髪の毛が！
Hair!
めぐね...
It's overlapping...
静電気が！
Static electricity!
団長、つまり電気の塊なんだね。
So Dancho, you're basically a clump of electricity.
そうかもしれん、団長。
That might be true.
どういうフリ？
What kind of set-up is that?
適応できなかった。
I couldn't adapt.
ちょっと無茶振りがすぎたらしい。他は？
Apparently it was too much of a curveball. Anything else?
みんな「草草」とか「てぇてぇ」とか言ってる。
Everyone's saying "lol lol" or "teetee."
草とてぇてぇは一緒じゃなくね？
Aren't "lol" and "teetee" different?
なかなか本当に我らアイドルなのにアイドルポーズが分からないんだよ。
Even though we're idols, we really don't know any idol poses.
ハグ。
Hug.
じゃあ待って、ノエちゃんの思うさ...
Then wait, Noel-chan's idea of...
これがノエちゃんの思うアイドル？
Is this Noel-chan's idea of an idol?
でもなんか、ちゃんとハグできたね。
But we managed to hug properly.
いつもなんか上手くいかなくて失敗しちゃって。
Usually it doesn't go well and we fail.
私の女です。
She's my girl.
うちの、うちの...団長。
Our, our... Dancho.
ちょっとね、みんなには見えないけどここにも指輪が。
Wait, you guys can't see it, but there's a ring here too.
あ、今日ね、つけてる。
Ah, we're wearing them today.
手袋で見えないけど。
Can't see through the gloves though.
ちゃんとね、内側に。
Properly, on the inside.
本当にだもん。お揃いだもん。
It's true. We're matching.
本当にだもん。二人でつけてる。
It's true. We're both wearing them.
つけてるんだ。
We are.
嬉しい。
I'm happy.
でもね、指輪はあんまり見せびらかすものじゃないんだよ。
But you know, rings aren't something to show off.
まぁ確かにね。
Well, that's true.
ひっそりと輝かせるものだから。
They are things to let shine quietly.
見てー！
Look!
言ってるそばから自慢してんじゃん。
You're bragging right after saying that.
ノエちゃんとお久しぶりじゃない？
Noel-chan, hasn't it been a while?
そうなんだ、久々。
That's right, a long time.
そうだよね。お久しぶり。
Right. Long time no see.
なんか、余所余所しかったね。
You've been a bit distant.
いや、違うねん。
No, that's not it.
そんなことないよ。仲良くね、やってて。
That's not true. We've been getting along well.
いきなりそんな誕生日配信に何を。
Why say that suddenly on a birthday stream?
ノエフラ、今日なんですか？
Noe-fura, what is it today?
違う、やっぱほら、あのね...
No, it's just, you know...
フレアにもこれ、交流関係っていうのがあるから。
Flare has her own social circle too.
やっぱ妻として、そういうのをこうやって見守るっていう係が。
As your wife, I have a duty to watch over that.
私知ってるよ。ノエちゃんが配信でね...
I know. Noel-chan said on her stream...
「いや、団長フレアを誘うんだ」って。
"I'll invite Flare."
「とりあえず言うけど誘わない」って。
"I'll say it for now, but I won't invite her."
何、そのノエちゃんステップ何？
What's that? What's that Noel-chan step?
いや、誘ったりはしちゃう。
No, I do invite you.
ノエちゃんね、なんかあの...
Noel-chan is kind of like...
はあちゃまとちょっと似てるところがあって。
A bit like Haachama.
たまたまね。まさかの はあと様。
It just happened. Unexpectedly, Hato-sama.
なんかね。あの、そう。やろうよーみたいなね、
Well, yeah. Like, we talked about doing this,
一瞬声かかるんだけど「いつにする？」が進まないやつ。
and we'd agree, but then we'd never decide when.
え、なんか、いや今日は会えるから、
Well, since we could meet today,
今日ほら、そのあと、そのあと、そのあとって！
I was like, today! After this, after this, after this!
でも、そう、でも今日はね、なんか是が非でも来るからって、
But yeah, today, Nu-chan said she'd come no matter what,
ぬーちゃんが言ってくれてたんですよ。
she really made an effort for me.
絶対行くぜー！って言って。こうやって。
She was like, "I'm definitely going!" Like that.
そう、なんかぬーちゃんちょっとさ、先日体調、
Yeah, because Nu-chan was, well, recently her health...
ちょっと頑張りすぎて崩し気味って... 私がねちょっと...
She worked a bit too hard and was feeling unwell... I was...
でも、お、もう治ったから。ぴょんぴょん跳ねれます。
But, I'm already better. I can hop and jump now.
「大丈夫？」って聞いたらね、「絶対行くから」って。
When I asked if she was okay, she said "I'm definitely going."
そうそうそうそう。でした。ありがとう！
That's right. Thank you so much!
いや本当にもうちょっと、お邪魔させていただいて、
No, really, thank you for letting me join you,
ありがとうございます、こんな素敵な。正直、
and for such a wonderful time. Honestly,
2曲、2曲がすごく良かったから、団長本当に、
the first two songs were so good, that I wondered,
3曲目にあの「チューリングラブ」本当にいいのかなって思いながらも。
if "Tuning Love" as the third song would be okay.
ま、でもね、私は、ぬーちゃんと練習とかでさ、
Well, but you know, when we were practicing together,
歌ってさ、「あんまり上手く歌えないよー」って言ってさ、
you were like, "I can't sing it very well,"
「とりあえず1回試しに、自分の歌がどれくらい下手なのか」っていうのを試し録りしたの。
and you recorded a test to see "how bad your singing was."
何それ？どういうこと？
What was that about? What do you mean?
そう。で、なんか聞いて、「あ、なんか頑張らなきゃなー」って。
Yeah. And after listening to it, you felt like you had to work hard.
あー、でも団長でも最初、早口どうしても言えなかったんだけど、
Ah, but at first, I really couldn't do the fast-paced parts,
でもまあまあ言えたからいいんじゃないかなと。
but I managed them somewhat well, so I think it's okay.
練習の成果あったね！
Your practice really paid off!
成果あった。マジで最初やばかったからね。
It did. It was really bad at first.
「ちょっともうダメかもしれん」って言ってたもんね。
You were saying, "I might not be able to do this."
言ってた言ってた。うん。
I was, I was. Yeah.
え、なんかスタッフさんがね、「もう、もうそろそろお開きにしてください」と。
Wait, the staff is saying, "It's about time to wrap it up."
え、お開きって、え、これから焼肉ってこと？
Wrap up? Does that mean we're going for yakiniku now?
あ、今までありがとうございました！バイバーイ！え、チュー。
Oh, thank you for everything! Bye-bye! *Kiss sound*
え、なに、2曲、2曲歌うの？次も？
Wait, what? Are you singing two songs? The next one too?
よし、頑張ろうと思って。団長ちょっと、次の曲はぬーちゃんいると地獄になっちゃうから。
Alright, let's do this. Dancho, the next song would be hell if Nu-chan was here.
あ、分かりました。帰れってことですね。あ、分かりました。
Oh, I see. You're telling me to go home. I get it.
ぬーちゃんまた一緒に歌ってくれる？特等席でじゃあ。
Nu-chan, will you sing with me again? From the VIP seats then.
ちょっと、あのさ、ぬーちゃんサンズと喧嘩しないでね。
Wait, um, Nu-chan, don't fight with Sanzu, okay?
サンズの着ぐるみいるんだよね、そう。いるんだよ。
There's a Sanzu mascot, right? Yeah, there is.
じゃあ仲良く見てるね、サンズと。うん。
I'll watch nicely with Sanzu, then. Yeah.
じゃあ頑張ってね！お邪魔しましたー、みんなありがとう！
Good luck! Thanks for having me, and thanks everyone!
あ、今も見守ってて。ぬーちゃんありがとう！
Ah, keep watching over me. Thanks Nu-chan!
やーね！見守っててね、一緒に。バイバイバイバイ。
See ya! Watch over me together, okay? Bye-bye!
はい。ということでですね、ちょっと一瞬お水を飲んでいいですか？
Alright. So, can I drink some water for a moment?
あれ、お水どこ？お水どこ？
Wait, where's my water? Where's my water?
あ、金つば帰ってきた。
Oh, Kintsuba is back.
あぁー。ちょっとね、ぬーちゃんを返してしまったんですけど、
Phew. I sent Nu-chan back, but...
返したことにはちょっと理由がありまして。
there's actually a reason for that.
次の曲なんですけど、次の曲はですね、ちょっとヒントをみんなに出したいと思う。
About the next song... I want to give everyone a hint.
最近10周年を迎えた作品って何ですか？
What project recently celebrated its 10th anniversary?
知ってる人いるかな？
Does anyone know?
ちらっ、ちらっ。
Glance, glance.
ちらっ、ちらっ。若干のコメント時差がある。
Glance, glance. There's a slight comment delay.
コメント当たりがいますね。ではですね、
I see correct answers in the comments. Well then,
今回ですね、つい最近新曲も出ました、
this time, a new song just came out recently too,
カゲロウプロジェクトから、ちょっと私一曲歌わせていただきたいなと思います。
from the Kagerou Project, I'd like to sing a song.
聴いてください。「RED」。
Please listen to: "RED."
だんだん目が回って
Everything starts to spin
夕焼けが燦々空に散って
The sunset scatters brilliantly across the sky
滲み出す雲に
In the clouds bleeding color
言葉が出なくなるのは何故？
Why is it that words won't come out?
遠回りの近道と擦り切れて線路
A roundabout shortcut and a worn-out track
湿った手を掴んだまま 林を進む
Holding your damp hand, we push through the woods
互い違いの畦道が湖みたいに揺らいで
The crisscrossing paths sway like a lake
蝉の音をぼかしたまま 立ち尽くしてた
Standing still as the cicadas' buzz blurs
夏が昨日を通り越していく 草の匂い
Summer passes by yesterday, the smell of grass
俄雨の温度混ざり合ったら
When the temperature of the sudden rain blends in
僕らが今日まで知らない日々は
The days we haven't known until today
数え切れない鱗雲の奥で確かに呼んでる
Are surely calling from behind the countless cirrocumulus clouds
泥に塗れた僕の手を零番道路に
With my mud-stained hand on route zero
難しってはにかんだ 君と僕とじゃ違うから
You smirked at the difficulty, because you and I are different
だんだん目が回って
Everything starts to spin
夕暮れが燦々空に散って
The twilight scatters brilliantly across the sky
思い出すほどに 言葉が出なくなるのは何故？
The more I remember, why is it that words won't come out?
口面に賛成なら笑って
If you agree with the mouth-service, laugh
遠くに遠く離れた君をただ
Just looking at you, who has gone far, far away,
見たことない色に染まった瞳で
With eyes dyed in a color I've never seen before
瞬きの一つもしないまま
Without even a single blink,
大人なんかにはわからない色を見てる
I'm looking at colors that adults just wouldn't understand
明け落ちていく日々の色を鮮やかに閉じ込めて
Brightly locking away the colors of the days that fade into dawn
色褪せぬように
So they don't fade,
思い出してしまわないように
So I don't accidentally remember them
遠回りの帰り道に通り風が吹いて
On the long way home, a passing breeze blows
一人ぼっちのサイレンが響いては消える
The siren of a lonely person echoes and then disappears
乾ききった蝉たちの叶わなかった思いを
The unfulfilled feelings of the dried-up cicadas
終わった夏の正体を僕たちは知らない
We don't know the true form of the summer that has ended
西日の奥から太陽の影が這って行く
From behind the setting sun, its shadow creeps along
暮れなずんで行く今日がもう少して終わるから
Because today, which is slowly getting dark, will be over in just a bit
だんだん目が回って夕映え燦々に滲んで
Gradually my head spins, and the sunset bleeds brilliantly
どうせだったのに涙が落ちてゆくのは何故
Even though it was inevitable, why are tears falling?
約束を散々ぱらに待って遠くに遠く離れた君はもう
After waiting so long for a promise, you, who have gone far, far away, are now...
僕と同じ色に染まって忘れよう
Let's forget, having been dyed in the same color as me
サヨナラの一つもしないまま大人なんかにはわからない色を見ていた
Without even a single goodbye, I was looking at colors that adults just wouldn't understand
今日の日ということも
And about this day too
あぁ～！
Aah~!
ちょっとかっこよすぎる～
That was a bit too cool~!
はい、本日最初で最後のかっこいい曲となっております
Yes, that was the first and last cool song for today.
いかがだったでしょうか
How did you like it?
いや今回ね、いやこの曲もね、あの、
Wow, this time, well, this song too, um...
Suu、パトラが作ってくれた曲でもあるんですけど
It's also a song that Suu and Patra made for me...
演奏ね、してくれたんですけど
They did the instrumental for me,
めちゃくちゃかっこいいんですよ
and it's so incredibly cool.
そう、曲がすごいかっこよくて、
Yeah, the song is just so cool,
で、あのこの曲どうしてもかっこよく聞かせたかったので
and because I really wanted to make this song sound cool,
ちょっとコーラスだけ事前にちょっと録らせていただいたんですけど
I actually recorded the chorus in advance,
どうだったみんな？ちょっともうコーラスめちゃくちゃ難しかった
How was it, everyone? The chorus was just so difficult!
でもコーラスが死なないように歌うのも難しかった！
But singing in a way that didn't drown out the chorus was also hard!
どう？初めて聴いた人もいるかもしれない。これあのカゲロウプロジェクトさんの曲なんでね
How was it? Some of you might be hearing it for the first time. It's a song from the Kagerou Project,
ぜひぜひあの元の曲も聴いてほしいなっていう
so I'd really love for you to listen to the original song as well.
はい、かっこいい曲、最高だった？
Yes, a cool song. Was it the best?
よかった、ありがとう
I'm glad, thank you.
やっぱかっこいい曲をかっこよく歌うっていうのは難しいな
It really is hard to sing a cool song in a cool way.
うーん、よかった。最高だった、ありがとう
Hmm, I'm glad. It was the best, thank you.
えーですね、あの、今回、あの、ご用意させていただいた曲っていうのは、
And so, um, the songs I've prepared for today...
実はちょっと次で最後、次でもう最後なんですよ
Actually, the next one is the last. The next one is already the last one.
早いね、あっという間
It's fast, isn't it? It went by in a flash.
なんですけど、あの、待って、まだ帰らないで
But, um, wait, don't leave yet!
ちょっと「最後の一曲聴いたからもう帰るわ」みたいな感じにしないで待って
Don't be like "I've heard the last song, so I'm heading home" — wait!
ちょっとまだもしかしたら、サプライズで何かあるかもしれない...自分で言ったらサプライズじゃねえわ
Because there might still be... a surprise of some kind! ...Wait, if I say it myself, it's not a surprise.
でも！でも！でも最後、最後まで聴いててほしいなって思います
But! But! But I hope you'll listen until the very end.
まあちょっと最後の、今回の曲はね、あの、最後の曲、えー今回のこの曲も、
Well, about the last song this time, um, the last song... this song as well,
まああの30代ぐらいのお兄ちゃんとか、お姉ちゃんとかに、
well, to the brothers and sisters in their 30s or so,
なんかめっちゃ刺さるかもしれない曲をちょっと選びました
I chose a song that might really hit home for you.
あの、誕生日に歌いたい曲だったので
It was a song I really wanted to sing on my birthday,
ちょっと聴いてもらえますか？
so, would you mind listening to it?
元々なんか歌いたい曲だったんですけど
It was a song I've wanted to sing for a while,
ちょっと歌わせていただいても...
so if you don't mind me singing it...
自分、歌わせていただいてもいいですか？
May I? Is it okay if I sing it?
ツイートよろしくね。あ、ちょっ、ツイートよろしくね。
Please tweet about it! Oh, wait, please tweet about it!
はい、ということでですね、では、歌わせていただきたいと思います。
Alright then, I'd like to perform the song now.
Wind Climbing ~風にあそばれて~
Wind Climbing ~Played by the Wind~
Wind Climbing ～風にあそばれて～
作詞・作曲：奥井亜紀
Wind Climbing ~Played by the Wind~
Lyrics & Composition: Maki Okui
誕生日を迎えるたびに
Every time my birthday comes around,
何を祝うのかがずっと謎だった
I always wondered what exactly we were celebrating.
見えなくなってしまったものは
The things that have faded from sight,
二度と帰らないと知ったとき
When I realized they'd never come back,
年をとることへの後悔と
I felt a sense of regret for aging,
一日が過ぎていく恐怖を感じた
And a fear of the passing days.
どうにもならない今日だけど Hey!
Today may be beyond my control, but Hey!
そんな道じゃきっとつまらない
A path like that would surely be boring.
君と生きてく明日だから Hey!
Because tomorrow is a day I'll live with you, Hey!
這い上がるくらいでちょうどいい
Struggling to climb back up is just about right.
脇道を一人歩くそんな自分に
Walking down a side road all by myself,
見惚れてみたり
I catch myself being captivated by that version of me.
歩き疲れた人へと
To those who have grown weary of walking,
冷たい言葉を平気で放つ
I would casually toss out cold, unfeeling words.
調子づいてた小さな自分
I was just a small person, getting carried away with myself.
風にあそばれてやっとここに
Played by the wind, I finally managed...
立っていた
...to stand right here.
どうにもならない今日だけど Hey!
Today may be beyond my control, but Hey!
そんな道じゃきっとつまらない
A path like that would surely be boring.
君と生きてく明日だから Hey!
Because tomorrow is a day I'll live with you, Hey!
這い上がるくらいでちょうどいい
Struggling to climb back up is just about right.
今日はお祝いに来てくれてどうもありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much for coming to celebrate today!
誕生日を盛り上げるためにみんなも一緒に
To liven up this birthday celebration, I'd love it if everyone
最後まで盛り上がってくれると嬉しいです！
could keep the energy up with me until the very end!
手拍子！
Clap your hands!
はい！
Yeah!
転んでできた傷の痛みに
For the pain of the wounds from falling,
見合う何かを求めたなら
If I sought something of equal value,
まぼろし
It would only be an illusion.
どうにもならない今日はせめて
Since there's nothing I can do about today, at least
笑い話に変えられますように
I hope I can turn it into a funny story.
君と生きてく明日だから Hey!
Because tomorrow is a day I'll live with you, Hey!
這い上がるくらいでちょうどいい
Struggling to climb back up is just about right.
どうにもならない今日だけど Hey!
Today may be beyond my control, but Hey!
そんな道じゃきっとつまらない
A path like that would surely be boring.
君と生きてく明日だから Hey!
Because tomorrow is a day I'll live with you, Hey!
這い上がるくらいでちょうどいい
Struggling to climb back up is just about right.
はぁ～...
Phew...
やっぱ、歌うときにさ...
You know, when I'm singing...
はぁはぁって言ってるのをさ、ちょっと、あんまり出したくないなと思ってさ
I didn't really want to let all that heavy breathing show.
お水ありがとうございます。
Thank you for the water.
思って頑張るんだけどさ、終わった瞬間にどっと...
I try my best, but as soon as the song ends, it all hits me...
ちょっと、お水飲みますね。
I'm going to drink some water for a second.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
この曲、やっぱりちょっと何て言うかこう
This song, after all, how should I put it...
エルフレのみんなもすごくお世話になってて
The Elfriends have also been very supportive...
なんかこの歌詞すごく刺さるなって思ってたから
I felt these lyrics really resonated with me.
誕生日には絶対歌いたいなって思ってたので
So I really wanted to sing it on my birthday.
本当に、楽曲、歌わせていただいて本当にありがとうございました
Truly, thank you so much for letting me sing this song.
そして、あの、まあ今日私のこと初めて知ってくれた人も
And, well, for those who got to know me for the first time today,
結構この曲、初めて聞いた人もいい曲だと思ってくれたんじゃないかなと思うし
I think even those hearing it for the first time found it to be a good song.
ね、あの、知ってる人も、知ってる人はなんか懐かしいなって気持ちになってくれたかなって
And for those who know it, I hope it brought back some nostalgic feelings.
思ったりします。本当に、本当に、
That's what I thought. Truly, truly,
みんな、今日遊びに来てくれてありがとね
everyone, thank you for coming to hang out today.
来てくれただけで十分嬉しいんですけど
Just you coming makes me happy enough...
あ、なんか待って？え？
Oh, wait a sec? Eh?
なんか今、運営さんからプレゼントがあるって聞いたんだけど
I heard just now that there's a present from the management.
ちょっと行ってきてもいい？ちょっと待ってて
Can I go check it out? Please wait a moment.
なんだ？何や何や、
What is it? What's going on?
なんじゃおらあああ！
What the heck is this!?
なんや...
What is it...
にゃん、にゃん、にゃんにゃんにゃん、にゃん
Meow, meow, meow-meow-meow, meow.
え、これ何？あのWelcome 2000って伏線だったの？
Wait, what's this? Was 'Welcome 2000' a foreshadowing?
にゃん、にゃん、にゃんにゃんにゃん
Meow, meow, meow-meow-meow.
え、何、これ運営さんがプレゼントしてくれたの？
Eh, what, did the management give me this as a present?
なんか髪の毛もね、可愛くなっておるー！
My hair also looks cute!
え、ちょっと待ってよ、そういうサプライズはさ、嬉しくて泣いちゃうじゃん
Wait a minute, a surprise like that makes me so happy I'll cry.
ね、なんかみんなからもいっぱいプレゼントをもらって、運営さんからもプレゼントをもらって
I got lots of presents from everyone, and a present from the management too...
え、しかもこれってさ、運営さんだけじゃないね、どう考えても父さん携わってるよね
And, this isn't just the management, Papa [lack] was involved too, right?
父さんありがとう
Thank you, Papa.
エルフの耳もよう隠れとる
My elf ears are well hidden.
え、てかこれ何？最近ホロライブがさ、
Wait, what is this? Lately in Hololive,
なんか猫耳流行ってるみたいな疑惑、これ運営さんの趣味なの？
I suspect there's a nekomimi trend. Is this the management's hobby?
運営の趣味だそうです
Apparently, it's the management's hobby.
きゅぴーん！じゃないんだよ
It's not 'Kyupiin!'
まあね、ちょっとこの、あの、髪型とか猫耳とかは、ちょっと後日
Well, about this hairstyle and nekomimi, I'll...
配信で、別の配信の時に、みんなに見せたいなって思います
...show them to everyone during another stream later.
本当にありがとうございました、素敵なプレゼントありがとう
Thank you so much, thank you for the wonderful present.
じゃあ、ちょっと一旦みんなのところに戻るね
Now, I'll go back to everyone for a bit.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
えー、嬉しい
Eh, I'm so happy.
ありがとうございます、本当に、本当に
Thank you so much, truly, truly.
みんなもありがとう
Thank you to everyone too.
運営さんも本当にありがとう。今日歌うことができたのも運営さんのおかげ、本当にありがとうございます
Thank you so much to the management too. It's thanks to them that I could sing today.
でですね、今回私からも、あの、みんなにね、告知あります
And so, I also have an announcement for everyone this time.
みんなにプレゼント、プレゼントって言いながら金とるんかいって
A present for everyone—though you might say, "You're taking money while calling it a present?"
でも、ちょっと一生懸命みんなに喜んでもらえるものとか考えたから、ちょっと見てくれないかな
But I thought really hard about what would make everyone happy, so please take a look.
じゃあ、ちょっと、どどん！
Now, here it is—dodon!
不知火フレア 誕生日記念 2021
4月2日 販売開始
ボイス＆グッズ全部セット
Shiranui Flare Birthday Celebration 2021
Sales start April 2
Voice & Goods Complete Set
こちら、不知火フレア、誕生日記念2021、ボイスアンドグッズ全部セット！
Here is the Shiranui Flare Birthday Celebration 2021, Voice & Goods Complete Set!
こちら、ご用意させていただきました。父さんがね、忙しい合間を縫って、私を可愛くお仕立ていただいて
We have prepared this. Papa, in between his busy schedule, tailored me to be so cute...
可愛い衣装で、え、今回書き下ろしていただきました。父さんもありがとう、運営さんもありがとう
...and drew me in a cute outfit this time. Thank you, Papa, and thank you, management.
で、グッズの気になるグッズの中身もちょっと見ていきましょう、お願いします
And let's take a look at the contents of the goods everyone is curious about. Please.
lack先生描き下ろし ブック型ケース
Book-shaped case drawn by lack-sensei
こちら、ブック型ケース。ちょっとね、私がね、今回
This is a book-shaped case. Since I...
なんかコンセプトを決めたくて、あの、なんか絵本みたいなコンセプトにしたくて
...wanted to decide on a concept this time, I wanted it to be like a picture book concept.
なので、あの、こういう本の形をした、あの、箱
So, it's a box shaped like a book.
だから、なんか領収書入れるとか
So you can put receipts in it, for example.
小物入れるとか、なんかそういうことができる箱になってます
Or small items, it's a box that can be used for things like that.
あるだけでもちょっと可愛いんじゃないかなって思ってみました。用意してみました、いかがでしょうか
I thought it might be cute just to have it. What do you think?
これだけじゃないのよ、もう一回、どどん！
That's not all. One more—dodon!
不知火フレアモチーフデザイン
ブックカバー＆木製しおり
Shiranui Flare Motif Design
Book Cover & Wooden Bookmark
こちら、ブックカバーと、木製のしおり付いております
This is a book cover and it comes with a wooden bookmark.
こちら本のタイトルがね、Wonderful Life
The title of this book is 'Wonderful Life'.
素晴らしい人生なのさ。私の人生、とっても素晴らしい人生ですということで、こちらタイトルついております
'It's a wonderful life.' Since my life is truly wonderful, we gave it this title.
はい、こちらもセットで付いております。木製のしおりも一緒に使ってね
Yes, this is also included in the set. Please use the wooden bookmark too.
はい、まだありますよ、どどん！
Yes, there's more—dodon!
きんつばぬいぐるみ
Kintsuba Plushie
え、これ、ん？
Eh, what's this...?
え、きんつばこれいる？すげぇ主張して...
Eh, does Kintsuba need to be here? He's really asserting himself...
ね、待って、すげぇ、私よりも目立つんじゃね？ちょっと、ちょっと！
Hey, wait, he's so... isn't he standing out more than me? Hey, hey!
ま、でもですね、あの、つくもさんからね、あの、私のぬいぐるみ作っていただいたので...
Well, but you see, Tsukumo-san made a plushie of me...
ま、一緒にね、あったらいいんじゃないかなって、前にね、ちょっとあの、エルフレにはね...
So I thought it would be nice to have them together. I mentioned to the Elfriends before...
あの、持ってるといいんじゃない？みたいな、ちょっと話を、してたんですけど...
...that it might be good to have one, we were talking about it...
ま、今回、こちらきんつばのぬいぐるみが、付きます！
...and this time, this Kintsuba plushie is included!
はい、良かったね、きんつばおじさん！
Yes, good for you, Kintsuba-ojisan!
何のSEだろ。
What kind of sound effect was that?
はい。でですね、今回、このセット、基本的にはグッズこのセットになってるんですけど、今回ちょっと、頑張らせていただきました。
Yes. And so, this time, while the goods are basically in this set, I worked extra hard on it.
はい、ドドン！
Yes, ta-da!
不知火フレア 誕生生記念2020
Shiranui Flare Birthday Commemoration 2020
はい、今回、特典ボイス、付いておりまして。で、え、直筆サイン入り...
Yes, this time, it comes with a bonus voice pack. And, uh, hand-signed...
ま、これは、数量限定になってしまうんですけど、はい、今回はですね、あの、サイン書かせていただきたいなって思っております。
Well, these will be in limited quantities, but yes, this time, I'd like to sign them.
ただ、あの、出た瞬間、速攻でなくなるみたいな、ね、そういうふうにはちょっと、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら...
However, like, I don't want them to disappear immediately the moment they're released, like they always do...
なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら、なら...って思って、
So, I thought about that, and...
あの、いつも、ま、ちょっと売り切れそうな、やつ、の、あの、枚数の、倍用意してるので、
...I've prepared twice the usual number of copies for items that tend to sell out quickly,
すぐは多分売り切れないんじゃないかなと、はい、思っています。
so I think they probably won't sell out instantly. Yes.
ちょっと一生懸命サイン書きますので、ぜひぜひ買ってください。
I'll work hard on the signatures, so please do buy them.
これ残ってたら残ってたでちょっと気まずいので、お願いします。
It'll be a bit awkward if they're left over, so please!
ボイスの方はですね、あの、5個付いております。なんかね、あの、ちょっとガチ恋向けがちょっと多くなっちゃった。
As for the voices, there are 5 included. Somehow, there ended up being a few more for deeply devoted fans.
でですね、あの、なんかホムラくんが、あの、「いい子にしてたらいいことあるかもね」って言ってたんだけど...
And then, Homura-kun was like, "If you're a good boy or girl, something good might happen"...
なんかいいことあるのかもねってことで、ホムラボイス付いてるみたいですよ。
...so there might be something good. It seems there's a Homura voice pack included too.
はい、ということで、こちらグッズの紹介でした。
Yes, so that was the merchandise introduction.
はい、あの今概要欄にですね、BOOTHのURL追加されましたので、こちらも、え、確認してみてください！
Yes, the BOOTH URL has been added to the description, so please check that out as well!
はい、まだね、なんか、あるんですよね。
Yes, there's still something more.
実は、あの、ちょっと、もしオリジナルソングを作るんだったら、なんか、ドゥドゥドゥドゥンドコドコドコみたいな、ね、
Actually, I was talking about how if I were to make an original song, I'd want something like "du-du-du-dun doko-doko-doko"...
そういうのを作りたいよね、みたいな、話を、してたんですけど...
...and we were discussing how I'd love to create something like that...
はい、あの、こちら、え、ご用意いたしました。ドドン！
...and so, I have prepared it here. Ta-da!
Smile & Go!
違うんかい。君と僕、え、君と紡ぐストーリーじゃないんかい。
Wait, that's not it! Isn't it "Kimi to Boku... Kimi to Tsumugu Story"?
はい、今回ですね、ちょっと忙しい中、運営さんとか、あの、関わってくださったコンポーザーさんとか、
Yes, despite the busy schedule, the management, the composers involved...
本当に、本当に、あの絵師さんとか動画師さんとか、ロゴとか作ってくださったグラフィッカーさんとか本当に、本当に皆さん、ありがとうございました。
...the illustrators, video creators, and the graphic designers who made the logo... thank you all so very much.
え、こちら楽曲がですね、iTunes Storeで、0時からフルで、販売が開始されるんですけれども、
This song will be available for full sale on the iTunes Store starting from midnight...
どんな曲かやっぱ聞かねーと、買えねーよなって、思いますよね。
...but you're probably thinking, "I can't buy it without hearing what kind of song it is."
なので、ちょっとみんな、あの、今回初出しになります、こちらの曲、ちょっと聴いて、最後終わりたいなって、思っております。
So, everyone, this will be the first reveal. I'd like to end the show by having you listen to this song.
こちらの曲、一体どんな曲なんでしょうかっていう、ね。はい。ぜひぜひ聴いていただきたいです。
I wonder what kind of song it is? Yes, I really want you all to hear it.
ではですね、ちょっと、最後、これでこのまま終わっちゃうんですけど、あの、挨拶はないからね。
Well then, it'll end like this at the very end, but there won't be a closing greeting.
本当にここで最後歌い終わったらもう終わりだから、みんな本当に、来てくれて、ありがとうございました。
Once the song ends here, that's the end of the stream, so thank you so much for coming.
改めて皆さんに、ちゃんとお礼をさせてください。スパチャとかも本当に皆さんありがとうございました。
Allow me to thank you all properly once again. Thank you all so much for the Super Chats too.
遊びに来てくださった方も本当にありがとうございました。よかったら、チャンネル登録とか、高評価とか、
To everyone who came to watch, thank you so much. If you'd like, please subscribe and give a like...
してくれたら嬉しいです。Twitterのフォローとかもしてくれたら嬉しいです。
...it would make me happy. It would also make me happy if you followed me on Twitter.
Subscribe to the channel.
ということで、最後みんなTwitter、忘れないでお願いしますね。
So, everyone, don't forget Twitter, please.
ということで、最後、盛り上がって、いくぞー！
And now, let's get hyped for the finale!
Smile & Go!
こんぬいー！準備はいいかー？今日はみんなで騒ぎましょう！！
Kon-nui! Are you ready? Let's make some noise together today!!
せーの！はい！はい！はい！はいはい！はい！はい！はい！はいはい！はい！！
One, two! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai-hai! Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai-hai! Hai!!
Smile & Go! 作詞作曲：福地佑／笹峰あやと
Smile & Go! Lyrics/Composition: Yuu Fukuchi / Ayato Sasamine
やって来ました　みんなに会える時間です
The time has come to see everyone
歌とかゲームとか見て欲しくて（耐久配信ごめんなさい）
I want you to see my singing and gaming (sorry for the endurance stream)
あっという間に過ぎてしまう毎日に
In the days that pass by in the blink of an eye
乗り遅れないように手繋ごう（もうちょっとだけ一緒にいよう）
Let's hold hands so we don't fall behind (let's stay together just a little longer)
乗り遅れないように手繋ごう (もうちょっとだけ一緒にいよう)
Let's hold hands so we don't get left behind (Let's stay together just a little longer)
気づけば隣にいてくれてありがとう どんな高い壁だって
Thank you for being by my side, no matter how high the wall is
(ハイハイ！)
(Go, go!)
ひとっ飛びで飛び越えて
We'll leap over it in a single bound
(ハイハイ！)
(Go, go!)
誰も見たことない世界に みんなで行こうよ！
Let's all go to a world that no one has ever seen!
君とSmile & Go!! 楽しんだもん勝ち
With you, Smile & Go!! The one who has the most fun wins
君とSmile & Go!! ハジけたもん勝ち
With you, Smile & Go!! The one who goes all out wins
ここに笑顔で集まれば 最高でしょ (yeah!)
It's the best when we gather here with smiles (yeah!)
僕らSmile & Go!! いつも全力で
We'll Smile & Go!! Always with all our might
僕らSmile & Go!! 遊びまくろう
We'll Smile & Go!! Let's play to our heart's content
だって (そうさ) この日常が大切な宝物だよ
Because (that's right) this everyday life is a precious treasure
Smile & Go!!
雑談配信 今日はまったり行きましょう
A chatting stream, let's take it easy today
たわいない話 聞いて欲しくて (聞いて聞いて ちょっと聞いてよ～)
I want you to listen to my silly talk (Listen, listen, just listen to me~)
たまにはお休みしようと思ったけれど
I thought about taking a break once in a while
やっぱり晩酌配信しちゃおうかな (用意が出来たら 乾杯！)
But I guess I'll do a drinking stream after all (Cheers once you're ready!)
ありふれたこの時も 一緒に過ごしたら
If we spend even these ordinary times together
いつの間にかキラキラと
Before long, it'll sparkle
(ハイハイ！)
(Go, go!)
何よりも輝いて
And shine brighter than anything
(ハイハイ！)
(Go, go!)
言葉には出来ない想いが 溢れ出しちゃうよ
Feelings that can't be put into words are overflowing
君とLet's Enjoy!! 歌ってみようよ
With you, Let's Enjoy!! Let's try singing
君とLet's Enjoy!! 心を一つに
With you, Let's Enjoy!! Let's become one in heart
どこにいたって優しさは 届いてるよ (yeah!)
No matter where you are, your kindness reaches me (yeah!)
僕らLet's Enjoy!! テンション上げでさ
We'll Let's Enjoy!! Raising our energy
僕らLet's Enjoy!! はしゃぎまくろう
We'll Let's Enjoy!! Let's frolic to our heart's content
きっと (そうさ) 明日はもっと楽しいこと待っているから
Surely (that's right) even more fun things await us tomorrow
Ladies and Gentlemen!
よそ見してたら置いてっちゃうから 最後まで盛り上がってきなー！
If you look away, I'll leave you behind, so stay hyped until the end!
耳の奥かっぽじってよく聴いて！
Clean out your ears and listen closely!
もっともっと楽しんで！ガチ恋していけー！ラストー！
Have more and more fun! Show me your serious love! Last part!
いくよー！せーの！3, 2, 1, GO!
Here we go! Ready! 3, 2, 1, GO!
ずっと見ていて 私のことを これから先も期待してね？
Keep watching me, and look forward to what's to come, okay?
予測不能なワクワクを 君に送るから
I'll send you unpredictable excitement
君とSmile & Go!! 楽しんだもん勝ち
With you, Smile & Go!! The one who has the most fun wins
君とSmile & Go!! ハジけたもん勝ち
With you, Smile & Go!! The one who goes all out wins
ここに笑顔で集まれば 最高でしょ (yeah!)
It's the best when we gather here with smiles (yeah!)
僕らSmile & Go!! いつも全力で
We'll Smile & Go!! Always with all our might
僕らSmile & Go!! 遊びまくろう
We'll Smile & Go!! Let's play to our heart's content
だって (そうさ) この日常が大切な宝物だよ
Because (that's right) this everyday life is a precious treasure
とびきりの笑顔でいこう Smile & Go!!
Let's go with our best smiles, Smile & Go!!
今日はみんな、生誕祭ライブ、聴いてくれてどうもありがとうございましたー！
Thank you all so much for listening to my birthday live today!
生誕祭 3Dライブ
Birthday Anniversary 3D Live